const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following types of necrosis is seen in a granulomatous infection by Mycobacterium tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Gangrenous necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous granulomatous necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Non-caseating granuloma","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Coagulation factors are proteins that flow in the blood in their inactivated form. During a vessel injury, they become activated. Thrombin and thrombomodulin complex inactivates which of the following factors?","answers":[{"option":"V and VIII","bool":true},{"option":"II and III","bool":false},{"option":"IX and X","bool":false},{"option":"IX and VII","bool":false},{"option":"Plasminogen","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"The specialized epithelium is present in which of the following lymphoid organ?","answers":[{"option":"Thymus","bool":true},{"option":"Tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoid tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 5-year-old boy comes to the outpatient department complaining of a painful and swollen knee. On examination, bleeding is seen within the knee joint but with no signs of physical trauma. His mother gives a family history of a maternal uncle who recently died of a bleeding disorder. Investigations show isolated increased APTT. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":true},{"option":"Hemolytic uremic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia C","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombocytopenia","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Innate immunity is considered to be the first line of defense against many microorganisms. Its major component includes which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"T-cells","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"B-cells","bool":false},{"option":"Skin","bool":true}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A girl comes to the outpatient department with complaints of epistaxis and small bruising on her skin. While giving her history she informs the physician that her sister has the same problem. Laboratory analysis shows that her partial thromboplastin time (PT) and activated partial thromboplastin time (aPTT) are normal but prolonged bleeding time. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":false},{"option":"Bernard-Soulier syndrome (BSS)","bool":true},{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia B","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia C","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Raynaud's phenomenon and fibrosis of GI tract, skin, and tissues are symptoms of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Polymyositis","bool":false},{"option":"Marfan's syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic sclerosis","bool":true},{"option":"Multiple sclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"DiGeorge syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Activation of which of the following factors results in the initiation of the coagulation cascade through the intrinsic pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Factor XII","bool":true},{"option":"Factor IX","bool":false},{"option":"Factor X","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VIII","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Most of the iron in the storage pool is in the form of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Apotransferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Ferritin","bool":true},{"option":"Free iron","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What is the composition of hemoglobin A (HbA)?","answers":[{"option":"α2, γ2","bool":false},{"option":"α2, β2","bool":true},{"option":"α2, δ2","bool":false},{"option":"β2, γ2","bool":false},{"option":"γ2, ε2","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What is the composition of hemoglobin F (HbF)?","answers":[{"option":"α2, β2","bool":false},{"option":"γ2, ε2","bool":false},{"option":"β2, γ2","bool":false},{"option":"α2, γ2","bool":true},{"option":"α2, δ2","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A person undergoes ileal resection. After some days he develops weakness, shortness of breath, and anemia. Which anemia can it possibly be?","answers":[{"option":"Pernicious anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic blood loss anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Myoglobin is a pigment. Which system of the body does it have a role in?","answers":[{"option":"Central nervous system","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatic system","bool":false},{"option":"Electron transport chain","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory system","bool":true},{"option":"Urinary system","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Hemostasis is a means of preventing blood loss. Whenever an injury occurs, which one of the following is the first step towards clotting?","answers":[{"option":"Activation of coagulation cascade","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of platelet plug","bool":false},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":true},{"option":"Formation of fibrin plug","bool":false},{"option":"Retraction of the platelet plug","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which interleukin is required for the growth and proliferation of all the stem cells?","answers":[{"option":"Interleukin-1","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-2","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-4","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-5","bool":false},{"option":"Interleukin-3","bool":true}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following mucin antigens is present in both ovarian and breast cancers?","answers":[{"option":"CA19-9","bool":false},{"option":"CA-125","bool":false},{"option":"MUC-1","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoembryonic antigen (CEA)","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"During the development of the spleen, mesenchymal cells are present between which layers?","answers":[{"option":"The two layers of ventral mesogastrium","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral and dorsal mesogastrium","bool":false},{"option":"Ventral mesogastrium and septum transversarium","bool":false},{"option":"The two layers of dorsal mesogastrium","bool":true},{"option":"Dorsal mesogastrium and septum transversarium","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"When the total storage iron is much greater than the apoferritin storage pool, the extra iron is stored in an insoluble form. This form is known as which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":true},{"option":"Transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Ferritin","bool":false},{"option":"Haptoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Erythropoietin is primarily formed in which organ?","answers":[{"option":"Kidneys","bool":true},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following does not have a capsule?","answers":[{"option":"Palatine tonsils","bool":false},{"option":"Peyer's patches","bool":true},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Thymus","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph node","bool":false}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"After a long bone fracture, when is a fat embolism likely to occur?","answers":[{"option":"After 1 hour","bool":false},{"option":"After 24 hours","bool":false},{"option":"After 1-3 days","bool":true},{"option":"After 1 month","bool":false},{"option":"After 1 week","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 34-year-old woman is evaluated at the hospital and found to have a large ovarian cyst. During surgery of the cysts, it is found to contain cheesy material, teeth, and hair. What is this type of cyst called?","answers":[{"option":"Mucinous cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Cystadenoma","bool":false},{"option":"Chocolate cyst","bool":false},{"option":"Mature cystic teratoma","bool":true},{"option":"Cystadenocarcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 60-year-old male presents to the outpatient department with complaints of burning micturition and fever. On examination, blood pressure is 90/60 mm of Hg, and heart rate is 110 beats/min. The physician also notices blood oozing from a cannulation site. A complete blood count shows low hemoglobin, high WBC count, and low platelet count. Further investigation reveals prolonged PT and aPTT. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hemophilia A","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic autoimmune thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"von Willebrand disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia B","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"In case of an injury, a deficiency of which of the following would impair the adhesion of platelets to the subendothelial collagen?","answers":[{"option":"Plasmin","bool":false},{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Antithrombin III","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinogen stabilizing factor","bool":false},{"option":"Von Willebrand factor","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"If there is a defect of the mesoderm, which cells are primarily affected?","answers":[{"option":"Nurse cells","bool":false},{"option":"Thymic epithelial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neural crest cells","bool":false},{"option":"Thymocytes","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is formed by complement activation?","answers":[{"option":"Membrane attack complex","bool":true},{"option":"Antibodies","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"Antigens","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A patient was given a few milliliters of blood after which he developed an immediate reaction consisting of fever, hypotension, tachypnea, and tachycardia. Which of the following is true about this kind of reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Host cells and donor complement proteins react","bool":false},{"option":"Donor cells and host complement proteins react","bool":false},{"option":"Donor antibodies attack host cells","bool":false},{"option":"The reaction is due to preformed IgE granules","bool":false},{"option":"Host antibodies attack donor cells","bool":true}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"The receptor for IgG is present on phagocytes. Which of the following are phagocytes?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages and lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophage and neutrophils","bool":true},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is not an example of an antibody-mediated response?","answers":[{"option":"Graft-versus-host disease","bool":true},{"option":"Blood transfusion reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Drug-induced hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Rh incompatibility at birth","bool":false},{"option":"Autoimmune disease","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding individuals with blood group A?","answers":[{"option":"They may give blood for transfusion to person of blood group O","bool":false},{"option":"They may have phenotype AB","bool":false},{"option":"They may have children with blood group A and O only","bool":false},{"option":"They have B antigens","bool":false},{"option":"They have anti-B antibodies in their plasma","bool":true}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 13-year-old girl falls and hits her head on the wall, leading to trauma of the blood vessels. Tissue thromboplastin will be released by the endothelial cells. Which of the following factors will be involved in initiating coagulation?","answers":[{"option":"High-molecular-weight kininogen (HMWK)","bool":false},{"option":"Factor XII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor IX","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":true}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What are plasma cells derived from?","answers":[{"option":"Megakaryocytes","bool":false},{"option":"B lymphocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Astrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is not an antibody-mediated disease?","answers":[{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenia (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":true},{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Urticaria","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following lymphatic tissues is characterized by the presence of subcapsular sinus?","answers":[{"option":"Spleen","bool":false},{"option":"Tonsil","bool":false},{"option":"Thymus","bool":false},{"option":"Peyer's patch","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph node","bool":true}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which model of disease causation is used when agent, host, and environment are considered?","answers":[{"option":"Population pyramid","bool":false},{"option":"Wheel model","bool":false},{"option":"Web of causation","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemiological triad","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following components are involved in the first step of heme synthesis?","answers":[{"option":"Succinyl CoA and serine","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Malonyl CoA and glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Succinyl CoA and glycine","bool":true},{"option":"Malonyl CoA and serine","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibody acts as a B cell antigen receptor and plays a role in B cell maturation, maintenance, silencing, and activation?","answers":[{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":true},{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which type of cancer is the squamous cell carcinoma of the lungs?","answers":[{"option":"Benign tumor of epithelium","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant tumor of mesenchyme","bool":false},{"option":"Malignant tumor of epithelium","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Benign tumor of mesenchyme","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is used to detect hereditary spherocytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Serum B12 levels","bool":false},{"option":"Osmotic fragility test","bool":true},{"option":"MCHC","bool":false},{"option":"MCV","bool":false},{"option":"RBC count","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is the first clotting factor that is common in both extrinsic and intrinsic pathway?","answers":[{"option":"Factor II","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V","bool":false},{"option":"Factor IX","bool":false},{"option":"Factor X","bool":true}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Hemophilia A is characterized by the deficiency of which factors?","answers":[{"option":"Factor IX","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue factor","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VIII","bool":true},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor X","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is an indication for prenatal diagnostic tests?","answers":[{"option":"Mother taking no medication","bool":false},{"option":"Family history of cigarette smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Past history of neural tube defects","bool":true},{"option":"Maternal age < 15 years","bool":false},{"option":"Maternal age < 30 years","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is incorrect regarding the histology of the spleen?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils are the predominant cells of the periarteriolar lymphoid sheaths (PALS)","bool":true},{"option":"White pulp contains leukocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Littoral cells are found in splenic sinusoids","bool":false},{"option":"Red pulp contains sinusoids","bool":false},{"option":"The spleen contains cords of Billroth","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following results from the deficiency of uroporphyrinogen decarboxylase?","answers":[{"option":"Acute intermittent porphyria","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary coproporphyria","bool":false},{"option":"Sideroblastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Variegate porphyria","bool":false},{"option":"Porphyria cutanea tarda","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"To slow down the coagulation process, thrombin binds to which of the following proteins?","answers":[{"option":"Protein C","bool":false},{"option":"Protein S","bool":false},{"option":"Factor V","bool":false},{"option":"Thrombomodulin","bool":true},{"option":"Factor VIII","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A first-year medical student has a fever and sore throat. The physician prescribes Ibuprofen. Which process is involved in relieving the pain and fever?","answers":[{"option":"It irreversibly inhibits cyclooxygenase, reducing prostaglandin production","bool":false},{"option":"It reversibly inhibits phospholipase A2, reducing arachidonic acid production","bool":false},{"option":"It reversibly inhibits cyclooxygenase, reducing prostaglandin production","bool":true},{"option":"It irreversibly inhibits phospholipase A2, reducing arachidonic acid production","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A venous embolism is likely to cause an infarct in which of the following organs?","answers":[{"option":"Alll of these","bool":false},{"option":"Lung","bool":true},{"option":"Kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Testis","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What is the sudden occurrence of cases in a relatively larger geographical area with more than one focal point known as?","answers":[{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false},{"option":"Outbreak","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":false},{"option":"Epidemic","bool":true},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following lymphoid organs has stratified squamous epithelial lining?","answers":[{"option":"Thymus","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph nodes","bool":false},{"option":"Palatine tonsil","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Spleen","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following factors is deficient in hemophilia B?","answers":[{"option":"Factor X","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VIII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor IX","bool":true},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":false},{"option":"Tissue factor","bool":false}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following leads to a decrease in plasma oncotic pressure?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphatic obstruction","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperproteinemia","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma albumin decrement","bool":true}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding hereditary spherocytosis?","answers":[{"option":"Spherocytes with increased central pallor","bool":false},{"option":"Increased osmotic fragility","bool":true},{"option":"Low MCHC","bool":false},{"option":"High MCV","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"In the oxygen-hemoglobin dissociation curve, a decrease in pH will lead to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Increased affinity of hemoglobin to CO2","bool":false},{"option":"No change","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased affinity of hemoglobin to CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Curve shift to the left","bool":false},{"option":"Curve shift to the right","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is correct regarding the factors affecting the affinity of hemoglobin for O2?","answers":[{"option":"Increases with decrease in pH","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases with increase in 2,3-BPG","bool":true},{"option":"Increases with increase in CO2","bool":false},{"option":"Increases with increase in temperature","bool":false},{"option":"Decreases with increase in pH","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Congenital deficiency of a specific protein leads to the inability to transport conjugated bilirubin out of the liver and into the bile. This statement is most relevant for which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Crigler-Najjar syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Gilbert syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Physiologic jaundice of the newborn","bool":false},{"option":"Dubin-Johnson syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Obstructive jaundice","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Blood is a special type of connective tissue. Which of the following is correct regarding it?","answers":[{"option":"It contains fibers only","bool":false},{"option":"It contains both cells and fibers","bool":false},{"option":"It has a greater proportion of cells as compared to fibers","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Its ground substance is of a fluid nature","bool":true}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibody is found in the respiratory and digestive lining, as well as the saliva, tears, and breast milk?","answers":[{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":true},{"option":"IgG","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibody crosses the placenta during erythroblastosis fetalis?","answers":[{"option":"IgG","bool":true},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibody is dimeric with a J chain?","answers":[{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":true},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibody has a pentameric structure?","answers":[{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgM","bool":true},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":false},{"option":"IgA","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibody isotype is the most abundant in serum?","answers":[{"option":"IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgG","bool":true},{"option":"IgM","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following may result from frequent blood transfusions?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Wilson disease","bool":false},{"option":"Hemochromatosis","bool":true},{"option":"Anemia of chronic disease","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which type of hemoglobin prevents symptoms of thalassemia from appearing in neonatal life?","answers":[{"option":"HbC","bool":false},{"option":"HbA","bool":false},{"option":"HbS","bool":false},{"option":"HbA2","bool":false},{"option":"HbF","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which protein plays a major role in maintaining oncotic pressure and transportation of lipids and steroids?","answers":[{"option":"C-reactive protein (CRP)","bool":false},{"option":"Albumin","bool":true},{"option":"Fibrinogen","bool":false},{"option":"Haptoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Globulin","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"How many oxygen molecules bind to a single hemoglobin molecule?","answers":[{"option":"4","bool":true},{"option":"8","bool":false},{"option":"3","bool":false},{"option":"16","bool":false},{"option":"2","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What is secreted as a result of degranulation of platelets?","answers":[{"option":"Prostaglandins","bool":false},{"option":"NO (nitric oxide)","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2","bool":true},{"option":"Lipoxins","bool":false},{"option":"NO synthase","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which chains are involved in the formation of hemoglobin A?","answers":[{"option":"2 alpha, 2 zeta","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha, 2 delta","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha, 2 epsilon","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha, 2 gamma","bool":false},{"option":"2 alpha, 2 beta","bool":true}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"The red pulp of the spleen contains which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cords of bilroth","bool":true},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Central arteriole","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"PALS (periarteriolar lymphoid sheaths)","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which antibodies are released during type 2 hypersensitivity reactions?","answers":[{"option":"IgG + IgM","bool":true},{"option":"IgG + IgD","bool":false},{"option":"IgD + IgE","bool":false},{"option":"IgM + IgA","bool":false},{"option":"IgA + IgE","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What is the most important value measured from a cross-sectional study?","answers":[{"option":"Prevalence","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Risk","bool":false},{"option":"Odds ratio","bool":false},{"option":"Incidence","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following prevents blood loss in a girl who got a cut on her finger?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary plug","bool":false},{"option":"Platelet plug","bool":true},{"option":"Vasoconstriction","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoconcentration","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrin formation","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Pyridoxamine, pyridoxine, and pyridoxal are forms of which vitamin?","answers":[{"option":"B3","bool":false},{"option":"B6","bool":true},{"option":"B12","bool":false},{"option":"B7","bool":false},{"option":"B9","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Palatine tonsil is derived from which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"1st pharyngeal pouch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal pouch","bool":true},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"2nd pharyngeal arch","bool":false},{"option":"3rd pharyngeal pouch","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which lymphocyte can destroy cancer cells without having to go through sensitization and hence is able to kill cancer cells in the first line of defense?","answers":[{"option":"CD8+ T cells","bool":false},{"option":"B lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Natural killer cells","bool":true},{"option":"CD4+ T cells","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis is an example of which type of hypersensitivity reaction?","answers":[{"option":"Type 2 and 3 hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Type 3 hypersensitivity","bool":true},{"option":"Type 2 hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Type 1 hypersensitivity","bool":false},{"option":"Type 4 hypersensitivity","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following factors initiates the extrinsic pathway of clotting?","answers":[{"option":"Factor III","bool":true},{"option":"Factor XII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor X","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VII","bool":false},{"option":"Factor VIII","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What of the following is the iron transporter protein in the plasma?","answers":[{"option":"Apotransferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Apoferritin","bool":false},{"option":"Transferrin","bool":true},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Ferritin","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Erythropoietin is produced in kidneys and other cells. What is the second major source of its production?","answers":[{"option":"Bones","bool":false},{"option":"Liver","bool":true},{"option":"Stomach","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal cortex","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenal medulla","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"The deficiency of which of the following enzymes causes erythropoietic protoporphyria?","answers":[{"option":"Uroporhyrinogen decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"HMB synthase","bool":false},{"option":"ALA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrochelatase","bool":true},{"option":"Uroporhyrinogen oxidase","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Complete lack of glucuronidation results in which of the following diseases?","answers":[{"option":"Crigler Najjar syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Gilbert syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Ehlers–Danlos syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Dubin Johnson syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Alport syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is attached to unconjugated bilirubin to form conjugated bilirubin?","answers":[{"option":"Albumin","bool":false},{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Iron","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Glucuronic acid","bool":true}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which protein shows the highest storage reserves of iron?","answers":[{"option":"Hemoglobin","bool":false},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Ferritin","bool":true},{"option":"Haptoglobin","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Deficiency of which of the following enzymes causes protoporphyria?","answers":[{"option":"Uroporphyrinogen oxidase","bool":false},{"option":"HMB synthase","bool":false},{"option":"ALA synthase","bool":false},{"option":"Uroporphyrinogen decarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrochelatase","bool":true}]},{"id":83,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following complement proteins is used to detect the activity of the immune system?","answers":[{"option":"C2","bool":false},{"option":"C1q","bool":true},{"option":"C3","bool":false},{"option":"C9","bool":false},{"option":"C5","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Most of the normal human blood is composed of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Clotting factors","bool":false},{"option":"WBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma","bool":true},{"option":"RBCs","bool":false},{"option":"Platelets","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of these is not a cardinal sign of inflammation?","answers":[{"option":"Pain","bool":false},{"option":"Confusion","bool":true},{"option":"Warmth","bool":false},{"option":"Swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Redness","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"In smaller vessels, platelets are responsible for vasoconstriction by releasing which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Thromboxane A2","bool":true},{"option":"ADP","bool":false},{"option":"PG-E2","bool":false},{"option":"NO","bool":false},{"option":"Prostacyclin","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"According to the report published in a newspaper regarding the cholera outbreak and a large number of patients were brought to the emergency department with diarrhea, vomiting, and fever. The district house officer asked one of his team members to investigate. What is the first step in the outbreak investigation?","answers":[{"option":"Write the report","bool":false},{"option":"Confirmation of the existence of outbreak","bool":false},{"option":"Confirm number of deaths","bool":false},{"option":"Confirmation of all cases","bool":false},{"option":"Verification of diagnosis","bool":true}]},{"id":88,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"In heme synthesis, Fe2+ is added to protoporphyrin to form heme. Which enzyme is needed for this process?","answers":[{"option":"Ferrochelatase","bool":true},{"option":"Ferrooxidase","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrohydroxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrocarboxylase","bool":false},{"option":"Ferrosynthase","bool":false}]},{"id":89,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which type of hemoglobin (Hb) is present in greater than normal amounts in beta-thalassemia minor?","answers":[{"option":"HbF","bool":false},{"option":"HbA2","bool":true},{"option":"HbS","bool":false},{"option":"HbC","bool":false},{"option":"HbA","bool":false}]},{"id":90,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"In erythroblastosis fetalis, which cells become abundant in the blood culture?","answers":[{"option":"T-cells","bool":false},{"option":"Immune cells","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Red blood cells","bool":true},{"option":"B-cells","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Secondary prevention is the method that helps to prevent any disease or injury. Which of the following is a type of secondary prevention?","answers":[{"option":"Health education regarding routine immunization","bool":false},{"option":"Treatment after a myocardial infarction","bool":false},{"option":"Screening for breast cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Prohibition of driving without driving license","bool":false},{"option":"Rehabilitation therapy after amputation of leg","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 20-year-old male has a history of sickle cell anemia and has repeated 2-year transfusions with a hemoglobin concentration of 8.0 g/dl. Which hemoglobin has a protective effect?","answers":[{"option":"HbC","bool":false},{"option":"HbA","bool":false},{"option":"HbF","bool":true},{"option":"HbA2","bool":false},{"option":"HbS","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which vitamin deficiency causes anemia?","answers":[{"option":"Β-carotene","bool":false},{"option":"Pantothenic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Folic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Biotin","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which statement best describes an adenoma?","answers":[{"option":"A benign carcinoma of muscle","bool":false},{"option":"A malignant epithelial carcinoma of glands","bool":false},{"option":"A benign carcinoma of fibrous tissue","bool":false},{"option":"A benign carcinoma of cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"A benign epithelial carcinoma of glands","bool":true}]},{"id":95,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A girl is brought to the outpatient department with complaints of gum bleeding, and epistaxis. Her complete blood count (CBC) shows a normal platelet count and prolonged bleeding time. There is a family history of a younger sister with easy bruising. What is the diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Immune thrombocytopenic purpura (ITP)","bool":false},{"option":"Drug induced thrombocytopenia","bool":false},{"option":"Glanzmann thrombasthenia","bool":true},{"option":"Hemophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin K deficiency","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A patient has been diagnosed with a malignant eye tumor in the upper right eye. His molecular analysis shows deletion of both copies of the tumor suppressor gene that checks the transition from the G1 to S phase of the cell cycle. Which of the following genes is defective?","answers":[{"option":"NF1","bool":false},{"option":"Rb-gene","bool":true},{"option":"K-Ras","bool":false},{"option":"p53","bool":false},{"option":"BCl-2","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following terms refers to the constant presence of a disease or infectious agent within a given geographical area or population group?","answers":[{"option":"Epidemic","bool":false},{"option":"Pandemic","bool":false},{"option":"Exotic","bool":false},{"option":"Endemic","bool":true},{"option":"Sporadic","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Atrophy of stomach mucosa damages the parietal cells that secrete intrinsic factor. This causes which one of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Hemolytic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Microcytic hypochromic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Megaloblastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following features of the adaptive immune system produces an\r\nexaggerated response?","answers":[{"option":"Antibody production","bool":false},{"option":"Delayed response","bool":false},{"option":"Immediate response","bool":false},{"option":"Antigen specificity","bool":true},{"option":"Memory","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A middle-aged woman with a history of rheumatoid arthritis consults her doctor. On examination, she is found to have splenomegaly. Her laboratory results reveal neutropenia and anemia. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Idiopathic aplastic anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false},{"option":"Felty syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":101,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Learning associated with reinforcement is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Innate behavior","bool":false},{"option":"Operant learning","bool":true},{"option":"Classical conditioning","bool":false},{"option":"Modelling","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulus presenting","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which protein does hemoglobin bind to after hemolysis of red blood cells?","answers":[{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Transferrin","bool":false},{"option":"Apoferritin","bool":false},{"option":"Ferritin","bool":false},{"option":"Haptoglobin","bool":true}]},{"id":103,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 60-year-old patient comes to the clinic with pain in his leg for over a week. He further adds that due to pain, he could not move his leg. He has now developed deep vein thrombosis in his leg. Which of the following factors is most likely responsible for thrombus formation?","answers":[{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyperglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Immobilization","bool":true},{"option":"Pain","bool":false},{"option":"Surgery","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"What is the maximum amount of hemoglobin a red blood cell can concentrate at a given time?","answers":[{"option":"34 g/dL","bool":true},{"option":"15 g/dL","bool":false},{"option":"25 g/dL","bool":false},{"option":"21 g/dL","bool":false},{"option":"19 g/dL","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A 5-year-old child, who has a history of eczema, develops rhinitis and develops asthma with seasonal change. What is the most likely change seen on the peripheral blood smear?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophilic leukocytosis","bool":true},{"option":"Basophilic leukocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Monocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophilic leukocytosis","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following keeps the clotting factors inactivated in the blood?","answers":[{"option":"Glycocalyx of endothelium","bool":true},{"option":"Nitric oxide production","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma membrane of endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Cholesterol on endothelium","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboxane A2 production","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"A middle-aged male comes to the outpatient department with a low to high-grade fever that has been on and off for the last year and has lymphadenopathy. Lymph nodes are discrete, enlarged, non-tender, and have a rubbery consistency. The rest of the examination is unremarkable. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":true},{"option":"Leukemia","bool":false},{"option":"Viral infection","bool":false},{"option":"Connective tissue disorder","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"1st-year/blood/2021","question":"Which of the following is responsible for anemia due to reduced erythropoiesis?","answers":[{"option":"Aplastic anemia","bool":true},{"option":"Sickle cell anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Iron deficiency anemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hereditary spherocytosis","bool":false},{"option":"Microangiopathic hemolysis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr